{"tossups": [{"question": "This man published the book <em>Dusk of Dawn: An Essay Toward an Autobiography of a</em> <em>Race Concept</em>, wherein he promulgated the \"Basic Negro Creed\" and discussed his break with the NAACP. This leader of the Niagara Movement died in Ghana shortly after promoting the <em>Encyclopedia Africana</em> and publishing several books on world peace. For the point, name this civil rights activist who popularized the term \u201ccolor line\u201d in his collection of essays, <em>The Souls of Black Folk</em>.", "answer": "W. E. B. <b><u>Du Bois</u></b> [[doo-BOYSS]] (or William Edward Burghardt <b><u>Du Bois</u></b>; accept pronunciation as [[doo-BWAH]])", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Sociology"}, {"question": "While captaining <em>The Flying Deer</em>, this man and his crew were killed by a rogue hurricane off the coast of St. Kitts. With the assistance of Flemish merchant Samuel Blommaert, this man used the ships <em>Fogel Grip</em> and <em>Kalmar Nyckel</em> to found New Sweden. This non-Swede's unintentional support of patroons who participated in the illegal fur trade led to the Dutch West India Company relieving him of his post. The island of Manhattan was bought for twenty-two dollars in beads by, for the point, which third director of New Netherland?", "answer": "Peter <b><u>Minuit</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man burst a blood vessel and died while giving an angry speech to the Quadi people on why they should cease raiding Roman lands. This leader from Illyria put down a Pict and Scotti attempt to seize the isle of Britain during the \"Great Conspiracy.\" This successor of Jovian put down an Alamanni incursion at the Battle of Solicinium [[soh-lee-KEE-nee-uhm]]. The father of Emperor Gratian was, for the point, which Roman emperor during the Crisis of the Third Century who was co-emperor with his similarly named brother, Valens?", "answer": "<b><u>Valentinian</u></b> I (or <b><u>Valentinian</u></b> the Great)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This man's family petitioned the Truth and Reconciliation Commission to not investigate his death to avoid granting clemency to the police. This person, the inspiration for the film <em>Cry Freedom</em>, founded the SASO organization following a conference at the University of Limpopo. In 1977, this Xhosa [[KOH-sah]] man was detained by Cape Town authorities following his violation of an order that prevented him from travelling to the province. The leader of the Black Consciousness movement was, for the point, which anti-Apartheid activist who was beaten to death by South African police?", "answer": "Steve <b><u>Biko</u></b> [[BEE-koh]] (or Bantu Stephen <b><u>Biko</u></b>; accept <b><u>Frank Talk</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A constitution in this language was authored by Lorrin A. Thurston and was signed \"under absolute compulsion\" by the king. This language, whose revitalization efforts have been led by publications such as the <em>Star-Advertiser</em>, has been heavily preserved on Ni'hau. This language was banned from schools in 1896 after a monarch was overthrown for attempting to rewrite the Bayonet Constitution. For the point, name this language of figures like Queen Lili\u2019uokalani [[\"lily\"-woh-kah-LAH-nee]] on a namesake island chain.", "answer": "<b><u>Hawaiian</u></b> language (accept \u02bbOlelo <b><u>Hawai\u02bbi</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this event, eleven rangers from the U.S. Marines were accidentally left behind at the Grand Anse campus and were rescued by the USS <em>Caron</em>. That, among other incidents in this conflict, led to the passage of the Goldwater-Nichols Act. Responding to the rise and subsequent military repression of the New Jewel Movement, this attack seized Pearls Airport and managed to rescue Governor General Paul Scoon. For the point, name this Reagan-era U.S. military operation on a Caribbean island following the deposition of Maurice Bishop.", "answer": "Operation <b><u>Urgent Fury</u></b> (accept answers involving the United States invasion or attack on <b><u>Grenada</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The <em>Tozama</em> were a subset of this class known as \"outsiders\" who were given <em>han</em> estates despite their opposition to the ruling dynasty. The rise of military governors known as <em>Shugo</em> eventually evolved into this title during the early Muromachi Period under the Ashikaga. A new aristocratic class known as the <em>kazoku</em>, which worked on a system of hereditary peerage, replaced this noble class following the Meiji Restoration. For the point, name these powerful Japanese lords who served as vassals of the Shogun.", "answer": "<b><u>Daimyo</u></b>s (accept Tozama <b><u>Daimyo</u></b>, Shugo <b><u>Daimyo</u></b>, or Fudai <b><u>Daimyo</u></b>; prompt on word descriptions like \"Japanese Lords\" before \"lords\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "While a sub-lieutenant, this man was captured after the scuttling of the <em>UB-68</em>, resulting in his imprisonment in a POW camp. This man gave the <em>Laconia</em> Order, which resulted in a rescue operation by the Axis after Werner Hartenstein unintentionally sank a British passenger ship. Following Hitler's suicide, this admiral served for nearly a month as president of Germany in a government with Chancellor Goebbels [[GEHR-buls]]. The creator of the \"wolfpack\" tactical model used by U-Boats, for the point, who was this Nazi admiral, the Supreme Commander of the German Navy during World War Two?", "answer": "Karl <b><u>D\u00f6nitz</u></b> [[DUHR-nitz]] (be lenient on pronunciation)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "During hearings with this group, Jerry Rubin wore a Santa Claus suit and a Viet Cong flag. Government official Alger Hiss was convicted of perjury after being investigated by this group for espionage. The \u201cHollywood Ten\u201d were blacklisted for refusing to testify in front of this group, whose members included Jerry Voorhis and Richard Nixon. Created in 1938, for the point, what committee in the U.S. House of Representatives investigated communist ties among citizens and public employees?", "answer": "House <b><u>Un-American Activities</u></b> Committee (or <b><u>HUAC</u></b>; accept House Committee on <b><u>Un-American Activities</u></b>; or <b><u>HCUA</u></b>; accept House Committee on <b><u>Internal Security</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In the 2010s, this event was linked to Hunnic peoples migrating from East Asia after similar samples were found in the Tian Shan Mountains. The Imperial response to this event was weakened due to the cost of recent annexations of the Vandalic and Gothic kingdoms. Court historian Procopius claimed that this pandemic killed over 10,000 people daily in Constantinople. For the point, name this \"Plague\" caused by <em>yersinia pestis</em>, often named for an ambitious 6th century Byzantine Emperor.", "answer": "Plague of <b><u>Justinian</u></b> (or <b><u>Justinian</u></b>ic Plague; accept Plague of the <b><u>6th</u></b> Century before mentioned; prompt on \"Plague\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This leader installed Parakramabahu VI [[pah-rah-krah-mah-BAH-hoo the Sixth]] as the final king of a united Sri Lanka. This man defeated the pirate Chen Zuyi at the Battle of Palembang during a series of expeditions documented in the Mao-Kun map. This leader brought back a giraffe from Malindi after visiting the Swahili Coast. This man\u2019s projects were stopped under the isolationist Hongxi [[HONG-SHEE]] Emperor following the death of his sponsor, the Yongle [[YONG-LUH]] Emperor. For the point, name this Chinese Muslim explorer during the Ming dynasty.", "answer": "<b><u>Zheng</u></b> He [[ZHUNG-HUH]] (accept <b><u>Ma</u></b> He; accept phonetic pronunciations)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This person spent a brief term as Secretary of the Treasury after William Duane was dismissed from the role. Charles Sumner was believed to have written a pamphlet that criticized this person\u2019s career, referring to him as the \u201cunjust judge.\u201d This person was a part of the minority who held that the president did not have authority to blockade ships in the <em>Prize Cases</em>. In a majority opinion, this person ruled that those enslaved were not \u201ccitizens\u201d under the U.S. Constitution. Succeeding John Marshall, for the point, what Chief Justice presided over the <em>Dred Scott</em> case?", "answer": "Roger Brooke <b><u>Taney</u></b> [[TAW-nee]] (be lenient on pronunciation)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "With Robert B. Owens, this scientist co-discovered radon while working at McGill University in Montreal. In 1908, this scientist won the Nobel Prize in Chemistry for discovering alpha and beta particles. With Ernest Marsden and Hans Geiger, this scientist conducted an experiment in which alpha particles were bombarded against sheets of gold foil. Often regarded as the \u201cfather of nuclear physics,\u201d for the point, what physicist discovered the concept of radioactive half-life and the atomic nucleus?", "answer": "Ernest <b><u>Rutherford</u></b> (or 1st Baron <b><u>Rutherford</u></b> of Nelson)", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {"question": "In one work depicting this event, a panel consisting of Melchior Inchofer [[een-KOH-fehr]], Agostino Oreggi [[oh-REH-jee]], and Zaccaria Pasqualigo [[pas-kwah-LEE-goh]] offered opinions. This event's central figure wrote the controversial <em>Sidereus Nuncius</em> [[NOON-kee-us]]. That figure at the center of this event was found \"vehemently suspect of heresy\" after publishing <em>Dialogue Concerning the Two Chief World Systems</em>. For the point, name this event involving an Italian astronomer who may have uttered the phrase \"and yet it moves\" in support of heliocentrism.", "answer": "<b><u>Trial</u></b> of <b><u>Galileo</u></b> Galilei (accept equivalents for \"trial\"; prompt on \"Galileo\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A philosopher from this city named Tertullian, considered the father of Latin Christianity, wrote the anti-Semitic treatise <em>An Answer to the Jews</em>. The Vandal kingdom promoted Arianism in this city, their capital, which was captured in the 5th century. After moving to this North African city, Saint Augustine of Hippo converted from Manichaeism [[man-ih-KAY-ism]] to Christianity. The biblical canon of the Western Church was confirmed at a council named for, for the point, which African city that fought the Punic Wars with Rome?", "answer": "<b><u>Carthage</u></b> (accept <b><u>Carthago</u></b>; accept <b><u>Qart Hadasht</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This leader defeated Anthony Pohlmann, a German who defected to the side of Daulat Rao Sindhia, at the Battle of Assaye. This British prime minister inspired the nickname for the \"Who? Who? Ministry,\" because he didn't recognize any of the names on the list of cabinet members. This general had the Lines of Torres Vedras built to protect Lisbon during the Peninsular War and led the Seventh Coalition in a victory which ended the \"Hundred Days.\" For the point, name this British general who defeated Napoleon at Waterloo.", "answer": "Duke of <b><u>Wellington</u></b> (accept Arthur <b><u>Wellesley</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Herodotus claimed that, despite its name, this ruler opened the Canal of the Pharaohs connecting the Great Bitter Lake to the Nile River. Bactrian governor Bardiya ruled for a brief interim before this ruler took the throne after claiming he was a son of Cyrus the Great. The Ionian Revolt prompted this man to plan an invasion of the Greek mainland which ended with a loss at Marathon. For the point, name this Achaemenid [[ah-KIM-uh-nid]] king who created the \"satrapy\" [[SAT-rah-pee]] system and brought Persia to its largest territorial extent.", "answer": "<b><u>Darius I</u></b> (accept <b><u>Darius the Great</u></b>; prompt on \"Darius\")", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "During a revolt in this city, Pedro de Alvarado led a party across a namesake causeway while fleeing during \"La Noche Triste [[lah-NOH-cheh-TREE-steh]].\" Sacrifices to Tlaloc and Huitzilopochtli [[hweet-zee-loh-POHKT-lee]] were made at this city's Templo Mayor complex. During a siege of this city, a woman named La Malinche [[la-mah-LEEN-keh]] helped the invading Spanish by serving as an interpreter. The capital of New Spain, Mexico City, was built on the ruins of, for the point, which Aztec capital?", "answer": "<b><u>Tenochtitlan</u></b> (prompt on \"Mexico City\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A sub-war within this larger conflict named for general Lennart Torstenson resulted in Sweden's annexation of Gotland, Saaremaa [[sah-reh-MAH]], and Halland with assistance from the Dutch Republic. During this war, Saxony and Brandenburg-Prussia led the formation of the Heilbronn League in the wake of the Battle of Lutzen. This war began when Protestants led by Count Thum [[TOOM]] committed the \"Second Defenestration of Prague.\" For the point, name this 17th-century war primarily fought in Germany, ended by the Treaty of Westphalia.", "answer": "<b><u>Thirty Years'</u></b> War (accept <b><u>Drei\u00dfigj\u00e4hriger</u></b> [[DRY-sik-YAH-rig-uh]] Krieg; prompt on \"Torstenson War\" or \"Hannibal War\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "General Arthur Percival was ordered to fight to the last man to defend this location, but instead surrendered around 80,000 troops. The assault on this city began with the Battle of Sarimbun Beach. Winston Churchill called the surrender of this city the \"worst disaster in British military history.\" This city's capture was the culmination of the Malayan campaign and involved Japanese use of bicycle infantry. For the point, name this \"Gibraltar of the East\" that fell to the Japanese after a weeklong battle in 1942.", "answer": "<b><u>Singapore</u></b> (accept Fall of <b><u>Singapore</u></b>; or Battle of <b><u>Singapore</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The United Christian Party\u2019s first presidential run occurred during this election year, in which Wharton Barker was the Populist candidate. The winning vice-presidential candidate in this election year had previously been appointed to that post after the death of Garret Hobart. The losing candidate in this election year lost his home state of Nebraska. Seeing a repetition of front porch campaign techniques, this election's winner gained support thanks to his victory in the Spanish-American War. For the point, name this election year in which William McKinley was re-elected.", "answer": "U.S. presidential election of <b><u>1900</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One set of entities given this task was nicknamed \u201cMickey Mouse,\u201d because their pennant numbers began with \u201cMM.\u201d The use of fiberglass and soundproofing became common in vessels designed for this activity, whose German practitioners were referred to as \"very much the unsung heroes of the Kriegsmarine.\" Right-clicking can lead to the setting of a red flag in a game named for this military task, which involves use of towed bodies such as \"oropesas\" to clip dangerous objects. For the point, name this task of destroying certain bombs in open waters.", "answer": "<b><u>Minesweep</u></b>ing (accept equivalents like <b><u>Minesweep</u></b>er; accept <b><u>Minehunt</u></b>ing before \"game\" even though technically different)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This man once told Alexander the Great, \u201cI am looking for the bones of your father but cannot distinguish them from those of a slave.\u201d This thinker disproved Plato\u2019s claim that man is a \u201cfeatherless biped\u201d when he presented him with a plucked chicken and said, \u201cBehold! I\u2019ve brought you a man!\u201d This thinker was an alleged pupil of Antisthenes and believed his teacher was the \u201ctrue heir\u201d of Socrates. Using an old tub as his home, for the point, what philosopher from Sinope [[sin-OH-pee]] was a founder of Cynicism?", "answer": "<b><u>Diogenes</u></b> [[dye-AH-jen-eez]] of Sinope (or <b><u>Diogenes</u></b> the Cynic)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "Files from this event were burned in a parking lot by a group of Catholic activists led by Father Philip Berrigan. A man donning a jacket cursing this event was the subject of a Supreme Court case in which an opinion by Justice John Harlan read, \u201cOne man\u2019s vulgarity is another\u2019s lyric.\u201d On his first full day in office, Jimmy Carter issued Proclamation 4483 which pardoned those who avoided this event. The Catonsville [[KAY-tuns-vil]] Nine and Paul Robert Cohen protested, for the point, what event that made it mandatory for men to serve in a certain conflict in Southeast Asia?", "answer": "<b><u>Vietnam</u></b> War <b><u>draft</u></b> (or <b><u>Vietnam</u></b> War <b><u>conscription</u></b>; accept equivalents; prompt on \u201cVietnam War\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Terry Holdbrooks performed this action after working as a guard at Guantanamo Bay for six months. The sura <em>Al-Baqara</em> warns against compelling this practice by force. The slave Bilal was one of the first people to do this action, though he was preceded by Khadija [[khah-DEE-jah]]. This action, which can be performed by earnestly saying the <em>Shahada</em>, was undertaken in prison by a man nicknamed \"Detroit Red\" after conversing with Elijah Muhammad. For the point, name this general action undertaken by Malcolm X in the late 1940s.", "answer": "<b><u>Convert</u></b>ing to <b><u>Islam</u></b> (accept equivalents; accept <b><u>becoming</u></b> a <b><u>Muslim</u></b> or equivalents; accept <b><u>Join</u></b>ing the Nation of <b><u>Islam</u></b> or equivalents but please explain that these things are not equivalent; NOTE: Be generous with answers; we are also not intending to equate the Nation of Islam with Islam as a whole)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "During an attempt to do this action, only 15 out of 400 settlers were found alive in Rey do Felipe by Thomas Cavendish. A leader of the Hudson\u2019s Bay Company named George Simpson was the first known person to accomplish this task mostly by land. The <em>Pelican</em> was utilized in an English attempt to accomplish this feat authorized by Elizabeth I and overseen by a man who fought the Spanish Armada. Francis Drake accomplished this feat, originally completed by a Portuguese expedition whose leader was killed in the Philippines. For the point, name this travel feat first completed by the fleet of Ferdinand Magellan.", "answer": "<b><u>Circumnavigating</u></b> the Earth (accept answers indicating <b><u>travelling around the</u></b> <b><u>world</u></b>; accept word forms)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The second movement of this piece was performed at the funerals of Erwin Rommel as well as the eleven Israeli athletes killed at the 1972 Summer Olympics. This symphony, the second movement of which is a C minor funeral march, was rededicated to Joseph Franz Maximilian and, ultimately, to \"the memory of a great man\" after Napoleon crowned himself emperor. Often considered the first \"Romantic\" symphony, for the point, what is this third symphony by Ludwig van Beethoven?", "answer": "<em><b><u>Eroica</u></b></em> Symphony (accept <b><u>Beethoven's Third</u></b> or Symphony No. <b><u>3</u></b> by Ludwig van <b><u>Beethoven</u></b> before \"third\" is mentioned)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Duke Jakob [[YAH-kohb]] Kettler began the first of four attempts to colonize what became this nation by the Duchy of Courland. The short-lived West Indies Federation had this city's port of Chaguaramas [[shah-gwah-RAH-mahs]] as its official capital. This majority Indian nation was named after Christopher Columbus spotted three adjacent hills which he called the Spanish word for \"Trinity.\" \"Father of the Nation\" Eric Williams was the first and longest-serving prime minister of, for the point, what country north of Venezuela, governed from Port of Spain?", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>Trinidad and Tobago</u></b> (prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A secret treaty named for this city promised that Charles II Stuart would end his conflict with Louis XIV [[the Fourteenth]] and convert to Catholicism at an unset date. Much of the force which planned to assist in Operation Dynamo, the planned evacuation at Dunkirk, massed in this port due to its relative proximity. This member of the historical \"Cinque [[SEENK]] Ports\" inspired the poet Matthew Arnold to write a poem titled for its \"Beach.\" Chalk makes up the White Cliffs of, for the point, what Kentish city, the former site of the Roman Portus Dubris?", "answer": "<b><u>Dover</u></b> (prompt on \"Portus Dubris\"; accept White Cliffs of <b><u>Dover</u></b>; accept \"<b><u>Dover</u> </b>Beach\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This author called the State \"as timid as a lone woman with her silver spoons\" in an essay that inspired a 1969 play by Jerome Lawrence and Robert E. Lee titled for the night [this man] spent in jail. That essay by this author defines a \"peaceful revolution\" as an event in which \"thousands choose not to pay their tax bills.\" The sections \"Economy\" and \"Where I Lived, and What I Lived For\" are included in a book by this author about his separation from society. For the point, name this Transcendentalist author of \"Civil Disobedience\" and <em>Walden</em>.", "answer": "Henry David <b><u>Thoreau</u></b> (accept <em>The Night</em> <em><b><u>Thoreau</u></b> Spent in Jail</em>)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "A controversial book by D. M. Murdock asserts that the origins and story of Jesus Christ are derived from the myths of this deity. Historically, a king or a priest would often play this deity in dramas in which they struck a hippopotamus with a harpoon. Those performances took place during the Hab Nekhtet, or the Festival of Victory, that celebrated this deity. The largest temple dedicated to this deity is the Temple of Edfu, built in the Ptolemaic period. For the point, what falcon-headed deity was the patron of kings in Ancient Egypt?", "answer": "<b><u>Horus</u></b> (or <b><u>Heru</u></b>; or <b><u>Hor</u></b>; or <b><u>Har</u></b>; accept <em>Christ in Egypt: The</em> <em><b><u>Horus</u></b>-Jesus</em> <em>Connection</em>)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "At a political rally, Donald Trump said this film, along with <em>Sunset Boulevard</em>, deserved to win the Oscar for Best Picture instead of that year\u2019s winner, <em>Parasite</em>. The main actor of this film almost boycotted its premiere upon hearing his co-star was denied entry due to the state\u2019s Jim Crow laws. The first African-American to win an Academy Award, Hattie McDaniel, won Best Supporting Actress for this film. Starring Vivien Leigh [[LEE]] and Clark Gable, for the point, what 1939 romance film is set during the American Civil War?", "answer": "<em><b><u>Gone with the Wind</u></b></em>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This man told Bernie Sanders that he forgot he was alive after the senator stated on Twitter that the \u201cextremely wealthy\u201d should pay their share in taxes. Kanye West appointed this man as one of his advisors during his 2020 presidential campaign. Anonymous denounced this man for prematurely branding himself the \u201cEmperor of Mars\u201d before accusing him of manipulating the Bitcoin market with his tweets. For the point, name this CEO of SpaceX and Tesla, the wealthiest person in the world as of 2022.", "answer": "Elon <b><u>Musk</u></b> (or Elon Reeve <b><u>Musk</u></b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "After a sculpture of this person by Antonio Canova was lost in an 1831 fire, a number of bronze copies were made by William James Hubard [[HOO-bard]]. The inclusion of both a cane and a sword in one sculpture have led to speculation that this person was meant to be compared to Cincinnatus. The year 1788 is inscribed in that statue of this person despite being finished at least three years later by Jean-Antoine Houdon [[hoo-DOHN]]. For the point, identify this person whose life mask and measurements were taken when the sculptor visited Mount Vernon.", "answer": "George <b><u>Washington</u></b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This person\u2019s demise was decided by the Supreme Court case <em>United States v.</em> <em>Sullivan</em> four years prior. Despite being in Miami at the time, this person was believed to have been responsible for the death of seven associates of Bugs Moran. This person said \u201cthey can\u2019t collect legal taxes from illegal money\u201d before being arrested by Eliot Ness on charges of income tax evasion. The first person to be labeled as \u201cPublic Enemy No. 1\u201d was, for the point, what U.S. gangster who ordered the St. Valentine\u2019s Day Massacre in Chicago?", "answer": "Al <b><u>Capone</u></b> (or Alphonse Gabriel <b><u>Capone</u></b>; prompt on \u201cScarface\u201d)  <b>Extra Questions </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In this state, German immigrant Bruno Hauptmann was convicted of breaking into the home of Charles Lindbergh and kidnapping their twenty month-old child. <em>The War of the</em> <em>Worlds</em> broadcast caused a minor public crisis after it claimed UFOs were landing in this state's municipality of Grover's Mill. The south side of Ellis Island was awarded to this state following a 1998 court case with neighboring New York. The first state to ratify the Bill of Rights was, for the point, what Mid-Atlantic state governed from Trenton?", "answer": "<b><u>New Jersey</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}